Hi and welcome back. In this lecture we will add a prompt to our MCP server. A prompt
is a reusable template that can help the user in a repetitive task. For example, if the
user is frequently asking the model to list the contentful entries and then translate them
into certain languages, then the MCP server can provide a prompt resource to help the user
with that repetitive task. Adding a prompt to the MCP server is very simple and very similar
to adding an MCP resource. We create a Python method and decorate this method with
MCP prompt and then we define the name of the prompt I call it Hill Translation. Then we simply
return the actual text or prompt to the user. Notice here we defined a variable called
language and this is the user input. So the user is required to provide a language and then
the provided input or the user input will be used to replace the placeholder in the prompt
text. Okay, let's see this in action. Right now I'm in the desktop application and then
I'm going to go to the plus sign and click on the add translation prompt. Now it asks
me to provide the language and here I will just say, I don't know, like maybe German.
If we click on the translation to text, now we can see the full prompt. So at this point
if I would just go ahead and click on enter, it's going to fetch the entries from contentful
space and then translate them into German. And let me allow this and while that happens,
please remember that as we said before, whenever you see a user input, you should always
think of an attack vector. So try to think what can go wrong here. We will cover many
attacks in section two of this course. So I hope that this lecture has been informative
for you and I will see you in the next one. Thanks for watching.